<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		<title>Smartstore - News</title>
		<link>https://smartstore.com/en/news/</link>
		<description>Smartstore - News</description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 12:43:36 Z</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://smartstore.com/en/news/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://smartstore.com/en/obligation-and-limits-for-sellers-on-ebay-and-etsy/</guid>
			<link>https://smartstore.com/en/obligation-and-limits-for-sellers-on-ebay-and-etsy/</link>
			<title>Obligation to report and limits for sellers on Ebay and Etsy</title>
			<description>From February 2023, private sellers will have to deal with a new tax regulation.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://smartstore.com/media/6896/content/news_steuergesetz.jpg?size=680" type="image/jpeg" length="65344" />
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;; font-size: 11px;"&gt;Image by &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://pixabay.com/de/users/scy-1147075/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;amp;utm_content=819285"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;; font-size: 11px;"&gt;&lt;u&gt;SCY&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;; font-size: 11px;"&gt; on &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://pixabay.com/de//?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;amp;utm_content=819285"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;; font-size: 11px;"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Pixabay&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More and more people are using platforms such as Ebay and Etsy to sell used or handmade products. However, &lt;strong&gt;starting
		in February 2023&lt;/strong&gt;, private sellers will have to deal with a new tax regulation. The Platform Tax Transparency Law (PStTG) was
	introduced to combat potential tax evasion in private transactions on these platforms. The law requires platforms to report information
	about profits from private transactions to the tax authorities. Rental platforms such as Airbnb are also affected by this regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Reporting Obligation for Sellers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new regulations stipulate that &lt;strong&gt;sellers who sell more than 30 items per year or earn over 2,000 euros&lt;/strong&gt; must be
	reported to the tax authorities by the platform operator. These limits apply per platform. This means that sellers who are active on both
	Ebay and Etsy must consider both limits separately. The reported information includes names, birthdates, addresses, tax identification
	numbers, bank details, as well as transactions and sales proceeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tax authorities will check whether sellers have exceeded the defined limits and thus qualify as commercial traders. Attention is paid
	to whether it involves used items and private sales or if someone regularly and commercially operates on the platforms. Regular rentals
	of real estate are also considered commercial trade. The main criterion for the tax authorities is the intention to make a profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a seller on platforms like Ebay and Etsy, you should now prepare for possible inquiries from the tax authorities. Accurate
	documentation can help prove the private nature of your sales. Keep a sales diary in which you record all items with purchase and sale
	prices. This way, you can demonstrate that these are private sales with no intention of making a profit. It is also important to note that
	the tax authorities scrutinize more closely if the same goods are sold repeatedly or if items are purchased at a low price and
	immediately resold at a higher price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Impact on Sales Prices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new regulations not only affect sellers but also the platform operators themselves. They are obligated to forward the necessary
	information to the tax authorities. For this, they must take appropriate measures to collect and store the data of their sellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="alert alert-info"&gt;Platforms like Ebay and Etsy have already taken appropriate measures to meet the requirements of the PStTG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction of the PStTG could also have an impact on sales prices. &lt;strong&gt;Some sellers may increase their prices&lt;/strong&gt; to
	cover the additional tax obligations. As a result, prices on platforms like Ebay and Etsy could rise overall. Buyers should consider
	this when making their purchasing decisions and may look for alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://smartstore.com/en/amazon-voucher-cards-latest-legal-changes-and-effects/</guid>
			<link>https://smartstore.com/en/amazon-voucher-cards-latest-legal-changes-and-effects/</link>
			<title>Amazon voucher cards: Latest legal changes and effects</title>
			<description>In recent months, Amazon has restricted the use of gift cards without any major announcements.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://smartstore.com/media/6893/content/news_amazon-gutscheine.jpg?size=680" type="image/jpeg" length="206201" />
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 11px;"&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://pixabay.com/users/kriemer-932379/"&gt;KRiemer&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://pixabay.com/photos/apple-gift-cards-coupons-1086439/"&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 11px;"&gt;Source: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://t3n.de/news/amazon-nutzung-gutscheinkarten-eingeschraenkt-gruende-1602166/"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 11px;"&gt;https://t3n.de/news/amazon-nutzung-gutscheinkarten-eingeschraenkt-gruende-1602166/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amazon has restricted the use of gift cards in recent months without major announcements. Previously, customers could use them not only for purchases on Amazon but also redeem them with third-party sellers on the &lt;strong&gt;Amazon Marketplace&lt;/strong&gt;. However, customers attempting to pay through a Marketplace seller now receive an annoying error message stating that their gift card balance cannot be used for this order. What is behind this restriction, and why is it problematic for customers?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Legal Changes as the Reason for the Restriction&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reason Amazon gives for this restriction is a legal change in the context of combating money laundering. The EU has stipulated that certain personal data must be collected for transactions. &lt;strong&gt;Previously, this only applied to gift cards with a value of 150 euros or more&lt;/strong&gt;, but in the future, corresponding identification obligations will apply even for lower amounts. While this regulation is still in the development phase, it is assumed that it will be in effect by the year 2025 at the latest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Amazon, laws for payment services require that, in some cases, &lt;strong&gt;customers provide identification information&lt;/strong&gt; when using gift cards for purchases from Amazon partners. However, the company emphasizes that this restriction does not apply to the purchase of products directly from Amazon. Customers can still easily use their gift card balance for Amazon's products and, after confirming their identity, for Marketplace goods.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Impacts on Customers and the Marketplace&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This restriction is particularly frustrating for customers who enjoy shopping with Marketplace sellers and want to use their gift card balance. Currently, &lt;strong&gt;about two-thirds of Amazon's revenue comes from the Marketplace&lt;/strong&gt;, while Amazon itself focuses more on trading core products. The Marketplace allows other retailers to offer their products on the platform, providing customers with a wide variety of options.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the Retail Association HDE, the previous threshold of 150 euros for collecting personal data has proven successful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Restrictions and Criticism Regarding the New Regulation&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The restriction on the use of gift cards at Amazon is due to a &lt;strong&gt;legal change in the context of combating money laundering&lt;/strong&gt;. Customers can no longer easily redeem their balance with third-party sellers on the Marketplace but only for products directly from Amazon. This restriction is particularly frustrating for customers who enjoy shopping with Marketplace sellers and want to use their gift card balance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It remains to be seen how the e-money issue surrounding gift cards will develop in the coming months and which regulations will ultimately be adopted by EU bodies. While Amazon, with its payment service Amazon Pay, already has the infrastructure to meet the new requirements, smaller retailers may face challenges in implementation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Customers wishing to redeem their balance with Marketplace sellers may now have to resort to alternative payment methods. This could lead to a more cumbersome and less flexible purchasing process. Moreover, it is questionable whether the collection of personal data effectively contributes to combating money laundering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critics argue that the regulations may be too strict and overlook larger money laundering problems.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amazon, with its payment service Amazon Pay, already has the infrastructure to meet the new requirements, while smaller retailers may face challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://smartstore.com/en/smartstore-ag-and-lighthouse-ivm-gmbh-intensify-their-long-term-partnership/</guid>
			<link>https://smartstore.com/en/smartstore-ag-and-lighthouse-ivm-gmbh-intensify-their-long-term-partnership/</link>
			<title>SmartStore AG and Lighthouse IVM GmbH intensify their long-standing partnership</title>
			<description>Shared paths for a comprehensive e-commerce experience.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://smartstore.com/media/6885/content/news-image-sm-lighthouse-partner-preview-2.png?size=680" type="image/png" length="5861" />
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The SmartStore AG and Lighthouse IVM GmbH are embarking on a collaborative journey and aim to emphasize their partnership. Through their longstanding collaboration, they have created a partnership that provides their customers with a comprehensive e-commerce experience supported by an ERP/PIM system and robust PC-controlled efficient warehouse and logistics solutions. The seamless integration of e-commerce platforms and automated ERP/PIM, warehouse management solutions is the key to lasting success for both parties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Customer-Centric Solutions and Innovative Technologies&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The partnership places special emphasis on customer-centric solutions. Both SmartStore AG and Lighthouse IVM GmbH work closely together to develop tailored solutions that precisely meet the specific requirements of their customers. Both companies can draw from success stories across numerous industries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The combination of SmartStore's innovative e-commerce technology and Lighthouse IVM GmbH's advanced ERP/PIM, warehouse management technology developed over more than 45 years results in a unique combination of state-of-the-art solutions. This provides customers access to innovative technologies that elevate their business processes to a new level. The partnership enables companies to stand out from the competition and offer their customers a modern and efficient shopping experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The partnership between SmartStore AG and Lighthouse IVM GmbH offers a range of benefits for their customers:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Efficient Warehouse Management&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An efficient PC-controlled order and warehouse management is crucial for the smooth operation of an e-commerce business. By integrating SmartStore's cutting-edge e-commerce platform with Lighthouse IVM GmbH's intelligent ERP/PIM warehouse management technology, customers can benefit from optimized and automated warehouse processes. This leads to a sustainable reduction in labor and warehouse costs and a permanent increase in overall efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Real-Time Data Integration&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The seamless connection between SmartStore's e-commerce platform and Lighthouse IVM GmbH's solutions enables real-time data integration. This integration allows for instant complex data transfer between the online shop and the ERP/PIM system, warehouse, resulting in improved inventory management and more efficient order processing. Customers can be confident that their orders are processed and delivered very quickly. Additionally, over 95% of item data maintenance is controlled through the ERP/PIM system, making item maintenance significantly faster and easier. This facilitates the transition to a SmartStore shop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Representatives from both companies expressed positive views on the partnership and the associated opportunities:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Together with SmartStore AG, we will continue to develop innovative solutions that not only impress with nearly fully automated business management but also in the external presentation of the business,” explains Hans Niemeyer, owner and founder of Lighthouse IVM GmbH.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We are excited to announce this longstanding strategic partnership with Lighthouse IVM GmbH. The combination of our strengths allows us to provide our customers with a holistic e-commerce experience supported by efficient, automated logistics processes,” says Pavlos Tsulfaidis, CEO and founder of SmartStore AG.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://smartstore.com/en/everything-you-need-to-know-about-delivery-by-cash-on-delivery/</guid>
			<link>https://smartstore.com/en/everything-you-need-to-know-about-delivery-by-cash-on-delivery/</link>
			<title>Everything you need to know about cash on delivery shipping</title>
			<description>Discover why this payment method is the ideal solution for some and can be more of an obstacle for others.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://smartstore.com/media/6869/content/news_bezahlen-per-Nachname.png?size=680" type="image/png" length="19574" />
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12px;"&gt;Image: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://pixabay.com/vectors/delivery-online-express-laptop-7070991/"&gt;&lt;span
				style="font-size: 12px;"&gt;https://pixabay.com/vectors/delivery-online-express-laptop-7070991/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cash on delivery is a popular payment method in online shopping. More and more people are opting to make their purchases online rather
	than going to physical stores. This trend has led to the offering of various payment methods, including the "cash on delivery" option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How does cash on delivery shipping work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cash on delivery shipping is simple and straightforward. When placing an order with cash on delivery, you select this payment method at
	the online store's checkout. The sender specifies the amount that the recipient must pay upon receiving the goods. The goods are then
	shipped to the recipient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon receiving the shipment, the recipient pays the specified amount directly to the delivery person. Payment is made directly to the
	delivery person, either in cash or with a debit card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pros and Cons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest advantages is that the goods are shipped immediately, as the seller does not have to wait for payment to be
	received. This saves time and allows the customer to receive the goods faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage is security. Since payment occurs upon receipt of the goods, the customer can inspect the shipment and ensure it is in
	good condition. This is especially important for sensitive documents or valuable items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, this method is a good option for those who do not have a credit card or online payment options such as PayPal. Payment can
	be conveniently made in cash or with a debit card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Although cash on delivery shipping offers many advantages, there are also some disadvantages to consider.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of them is the additional fee charged for cash on delivery shipping. This fee is added to the price of the goods and must be paid by
	the recipient. The exact amount of the fee depends on the shipping service provider but is usually at least five euros for domestic
	orders. Additional surcharges may apply for orders from abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it is necessary for the recipient to be present during delivery to pay for the goods. Delivery to the mailbox or to
	neighbors is usually not possible. This can be inconvenient if the recipient is not at home and needs to pick up the package or arrange
	for a redelivery attempt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Alternatives to Cash on Delivery Shipping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although cash on delivery shipping is a popular payment method, there are other options that can be considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative is &lt;strong&gt;payment by invoice&lt;/strong&gt;. With this method, you receive the goods first and then pay within a specified
	timeframe. This allows you to inspect the goods before making the payment and ensure they meet your expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another option is payment by &lt;strong&gt;credit card or PayPal&lt;/strong&gt;. These payment methods enable quick and secure payment and provide
	additional protection for the customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="alert alert-info"&gt;According to a study published by the EHI Research and Education Institute in July of this year, nearly 30 percent
	of customers made their online purchases through PayPal last year. Thus, the US payment service has surpassed invoice payment (23.8
	percent) as the preferred payment method of Germans. Direct debit/bank debit ranks third with 20.9 percent, followed by credit cards with
	about 12 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security in Cash on Delivery Shipping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cash on delivery shipping provides a certain level of security since payment is made upon receipt of the goods. This gives the customer
	the opportunity to inspect the shipment and ensure it meets expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, caution is advised as there can be cases of fraud. It is important to verify the order before payment to ensure that no
	unwanted or unknown shipments are paid for.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://smartstore.com/en/amazon-wants-to-speed-up-the-customer-purchasing-process-with-the-help-of-ai/</guid>
			<link>https://smartstore.com/en/amazon-wants-to-speed-up-the-customer-purchasing-process-with-the-help-of-ai/</link>
			<title>Amazon wants to speed up the customer purchasing process with the help of AI</title>
			<description>The online giant Amazon uses artificial intelligence (AI) to create summaries of product reviews. The aim is to speed up the buying process for customers who are pressed for time and don't want to trawl through countless customer reviews.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://smartstore.com/media/5512/content/Amazon_Retour_1000x562.jpg?size=680" type="image/jpeg" length="80356" />
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 11px;"&gt;Source:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a
			href="https://t3n.de/news/amazons-ki-bewertet-produkte-schlechter-kuenstliche-intelligenz-zusammenfassungen-1597916/"
			style="font-family: var(--body-font-family); font-size: var(--body-font-size); font-weight: var(--body-font-weight); text-align: var(--body-text-align);"&gt;&lt;span
				style="font-size: 11px;"&gt;https://t3n.de/news/amazons-ki-bewertet-produkte-schlechter-kuenstliche-intelligenz-zusammenfassungen-1597916/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The online giant Amazon employs artificial intelligence (AI) to generate summaries of product reviews. This is intended to expedite the purchasing process for customers who are under time constraints and do not want to sift through numerous consumer reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advancing development of artificial intelligence has led to a variety of applications that can assist us in various aspects of daily life. This includes E-commerce, where Amazon has developed an AI that creates automated product reviews. However, a recent investigation has revealed that this AI does not reliably fulfill its task, and the disadvantages outweigh the benefits for customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Product Review Summary Function&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2023, Amazon introduced an AI designed to automatically summarize product reviews, thereby streamlining the purchasing process for customers. The goal of this function is to extract the key points from numerous reviews and highlight the most important aspects of a product in a concise review. Customers are supposed to receive a compact overview, eliminating the need to laboriously read through hundreds of reviews and assisting them in their purchase decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Weaknesses in Product Evaluation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Bloomberg's investigation reveals that Amazon's AI does not reliably fulfill its task. Analyzing dozens of products, it was found that the AI is unable to appropriately filter and consider the highlights of the reviews. Negative aspects in the reviews are often overemphasized, and overall, positive and negative points of a product are not coherently listed. This leads to a distortion of the overall assessment and can mislead customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example from the investigation involves canning jars. Despite averaging a rating of 4.5 stars, the AI highlighted rust stains on the jars as a negative aspect. However, this aspect was mentioned by only 16 users out of a total of 3000 reviews. Nevertheless, this aspect constituted one-third of the AI summary, resulting in a distorted representation of the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Missing or Incorrect Information in AI Summaries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to overemphasizing negative aspects, the investigation also reveals that Amazon's AI sometimes fails to appropriately acknowledge important information in the reviews. For example, a backpack with over 21,000 reviews lacked the mention that inferior material was used for the shoulder straps. There were even instances where the AI turned a fitness device into a desk, rendering the product description inaccurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers have noticed these weaknesses in Amazon's AI, stating that the function negatively affects holiday sales. Despite this criticism, Amazon rejects the accusations and emphasizes that the AI helps customers find the right products, leading to increased sales. Additionally, the company continuously works on improving the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Challenges in Developing AI Systems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problems highlighted by the Bloomberg investigation illustrate the current challenges in developing AI systems. Artificial intelligence is not capable of independent thinking but merely complements the most probable next word. This can lead to misinterpretations and distortions, as is the case with Amazon's AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI-generated texts are unable to replace human thinking and judgment. They can only serve as tools to extract and structure information. When using such AI functions, customers should always remain critical and complement the information with their own research and assessments.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://smartstore.com/en/temu-mischt-auf-gamification-im-e-commerce/</guid>
			<link>https://smartstore.com/en/temu-mischt-auf-gamification-im-e-commerce/</link>
			<title>Temu mischt auf: Gamification im E-Commerce</title>
			<description>Die chinesische E-Commerce-App feiert vor allem in den USA große Erfolge. und dem Einzelhandel bereits 17 Prozent Marktanteil abgewonnen.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://smartstore.com/media/6830/content/news_temu_header.jpg?size=680" type="image/jpeg" length="49345" />
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt; Image by &lt;a href="https://www.freepik.com/free-vector/real-estate-searching-smart-phone_9906758.htm#page=2&amp;amp;query=app%20%C3%BCber%20lokalgesch%C3%A4ft&amp;amp;position=4&amp;amp;from_view=search&amp;amp;track=ais&amp;amp;uuid=9a4d84fb-7bc9-4dc3-b0e6-26d3adb77005"&gt;Freepik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Temu, die chinesische E-Commerce-App, feiert vor allem in den USA große Erfolge. Mit einem riesigen Sortiment von Kabeln bis	Haushaltswaren hat Temu bereits in den USA 17 Prozent Marktanteil gewonnen und zeigt, dass der E-Commerce-Trend zu unschlagbaren Preisen	nicht zu stoppen ist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Für Online-Shopbetreiber:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Temu punktet nicht nur mit niedrigen Preisen, sondern auch mit einem akktraktiven Verkaufskonzept. Der hohe Interaktionsgrad macht die	App besonders attraktiv und bindet Kunden nachhaltig. Onlineshop-Betreiber sollten die Entwicklung im Auge behalten und gegebenenfalls auf	veränderte Kundenpräferenzen reagieren.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Gamification als Erfolgsfaktor&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Der Gamification-Anteil von Temu hebt sich deutlich von Mitbewerbern ab und macht den herkömmlichen Dollar-Stores ordentlich Konkurrenz	ab. Dieser Trend zeigt, dass nicht nur Preise, sondern auch das Einkaufserlebnis entscheidend sind. In Zukunft könnten Verbraucher auch	hierzulande vermehrt solche Trends beobachten und auf derartige E-Commerce-Apps umsteigen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Einen ausführlichen Artikel zu diesem Thema finden Sie unter der&lt;a href="https://t3n.de/news/temu-e-commerce-app-1-euro-shop-bedrohung-1595656/"&gt; Rubrik E-Commerce von t3n.de&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://smartstore.com/en/dsgvo-schadenersatz-ende-der-abmahnungen-und-klagen-in-sicht-/</guid>
			<link>https://smartstore.com/en/dsgvo-schadenersatz-ende-der-abmahnungen-und-klagen-in-sicht-/</link>
			<title>DSGVO &amp; Schadenersatz: Die 5 häufigsten Abmahngründe 2023</title>
			<description>In diesem und im letzten Jahr waren Shopbetreiber wie nie zuvor mit Abmahnungen konfrontiert.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://smartstore.com/media/5473/content/Rechtliches_paragraph_Gesetz_1000x333.jpg?size=680" type="image/jpeg" length="75988" />
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In diesem und im letzten Jahr waren Shopbetreiber wie nie zuvor mit Abmahnungen konfrontiert. Im Mittelpunkt standen dabei Google Fonts und diverse Newsletter-Anbieter. In einigen Fällen waren die Abmahnungen mit einer Beschwerde bei der Datenschutzbehörde verbunden. Die Angelegenheit wurde für die Shopbetreiber nicht nur langwierig, sondern auch teuer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Der heutige Beitrag soll Ihnen einen Überblick geben, was sich in diesem Jahr in diesem Bereich geändert hat und was Sie beachten sollten.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In den Trusted Shops Blog-Beiträgen "&lt;a href="https://business.trustedshops.de/blog/legal/schadensersatz-ende-in-sicht-bei-abmahnungen-und-klagen" target="_blank"&gt;DSGVO &amp;amp; Schadensersatz&lt;/a&gt;" und "&lt;a href="https://business.trustedshops.de/blog/legal/die-5-h%C3%A4ufigsten-abmahngr%C3%BCnde-2023" target="_blank"&gt;Die 5 häufigsten Abmahngründe 2023&lt;/a&gt;" informieren Sie die Experten der Trusted Shops GmbH über aktuelle Themen rund um E-Commerce, E-Commerce-Recht und Online-Marketing. Die Trusted Shops GmbH ist Partner der Smartstore AG.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://smartstore.com/en/openai-steigert-gpt-leistung/</guid>
			<link>https://smartstore.com/en/openai-steigert-gpt-leistung/</link>
			<title>OpenAI boosts GPT performance</title>
			<description>The new GPT 4 Turbo can now go far beyond 100.000 character documents.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://smartstore.com/media/6696/content/openai-logo.jpg?size=680" type="image/jpeg" length="30312" />
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;OpenAI, developer of the well-known ChatGPT and other AI models, unveiled a new AI model this week on 6. November 2023 on his DevDay diverse	new enhancements, improvements and possibilities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;One of the highlights is definitely the new "GPT-4 Turbo model",&lt;/b&gt; which offers an impressive 128K		context window support and is more efficient than its predecessor. This means that instead of a few thousand characters		text, there are now very long input quantities such as complete PDFs, books and similar, with well over 100.000 characters of text,		and understand them. Most recently, OpenAI has come to the fore through developments by other providers, such as Claude 2 from Anthropic, in this respect		under pressure.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;GPT 4 Turbo should not only be more powerful, but also cheaper by making input tokens three times cheaper and output tokens	twice cheaper than in the predecessor model GPT-4 are priced.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smartstore will integrate generative AI like this into its solutions. This offers a number of advantages for store operators. The new	multimodal capabilities, such as image recognition and -creation and text-to-speech, make the store operator's daily tasks easier.	Complex expert tasks can be completed in a single step, saving time and money and improving sales opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://openai.com/blog/new-models-and-developer-products-announced-at-devday"&gt;https://openai.com/blog/new-models-and-developer-products-announced-at-devday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://smartstore.com/en/development-of-e-commerce-in-germany/</guid>
			<link>https://smartstore.com/en/development-of-e-commerce-in-germany/</link>
			<title>Development of e-commerce in Germany</title>
			<description>Study: EHI and ecommerceDB analyse online retailing </description>
			<enclosure url="https://smartstore.com/media/6540/content/news_entwicklung-ecommerce.png?size=680" type="image/png" length="132472" />
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10px;"&gt;Photo: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://pixabay.com/vectors/ai-generated-e-commerce-shopping-8261529/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10px;"&gt;https://pixabay.com/vectors/ai-generated-e-commerce-shopping-8261529/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The e-commerce sector in Germany, which has long been characterized by steady growth, recorded a decrease in revenue for the first time in 2022. According to a recent study by EHI and ecommerceDB, the top 1,000 B2C online shops experienced a net decrease of 2.8 percent (unadjusted for price), resulting in a loss of 2.2 billion euros, bringing the total revenue down to 77.7 billion euros. This marks the temporary halt of the continuous growth of the German online retail sector, which had extended over a period of 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Reasons for the Decline in E-Commerce Revenue&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The revenue decline in 2022 can be attributed to various factors. On one hand, some online shops are struggling with significant losses, while others are exiting the market for economic reasons. On the other hand, smaller online shops, in particular, have shown significant relative growth. Despite the decline, the overall revenue of the top 1,000 shops remains 1.5 times higher than before the COVID-19 pandemic. Nevertheless, the general consumer sentiment and online purchasing willingness in Germany weakened in 2022, leading to a declining trend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Growth of Smaller Online Shops and Slight Decrease in Market Concentration&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the revenue decline among large online shops, smaller B2C online shops in the lower rankings experienced significant growth of 7.3 percent compared to the previous year. This demonstrates that the German e-commerce market still maintains some diversity. However, the market remains highly concentrated, with the top 100 online shops accounting for more than 70 percent of the total revenue of the top 1,000. Due to the revenue declines in the large online shops, market concentration has slightly decreased. The net e-commerce revenue of this year's top 10 decreased by 9.7 percent compared to the previous year, representing 38.2 percent of the total.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Top 10 B2C Online Shops in Germany&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the ranking of the top 10 B2C online shops in Germany, there were some changes. While amazon.de and otto.de continue to occupy the first two positions, aboutyou.de entered the top 10 for the first time with a growth of 8.8 percent. Zalando.de maintained its fourth position from the previous year, displacing mediamarkt.de to the third position. In addition, there were two newcomers in the top 20: shop.rewe.de and bestsecret.com. The biggest growth drivers among the top 10 B2C online shops were apple.com (+18.2 percent), breuninger.com (+16.1 percent), and shop-apotheke.com (+15.9 percent).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Top 10 B2C Marketplaces in Germany&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study also includes a list of the top 10 B2C marketplaces in Germany. In 2022, these marketplaces generated a total revenue of 72.8 billion euros, representing a decrease of 2.4 percent compared to the previous year. Market leader amazon.de maintains its top position with a gross merchandise volume of 46.3 billion euros, followed by ebay.de (9.0 billion euros) and otto.de (6.4 billion euros).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;About ecommerceDB and the EHI Research Area E-Commerce&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ecommerceDB is a comprehensive database providing detailed information on over 42,000 shops, marketplaces, and companies in more than 59 countries and 18 categories. In addition to revenue and competitor analyses, it also includes information on e-commerce metrics and national e-commerce markets. The EHI Research Area E-Commerce analyzes the German-speaking B2C online trade and hosts EHI Connect, a platform for the exchange and discussion of current e-commerce trends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information about EHI's research and studies, visit &lt;a href="https://www.ehi.org/wissen/forschung/"&gt;https://www.ehi.org/wissen/forschung/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://smartstore.com/en/die-bedeutung-einer-digitalen-visitenkarte-wie-google-den-einzelhandel-unterstuetzt/</guid>
			<link>https://smartstore.com/en/die-bedeutung-einer-digitalen-visitenkarte-wie-google-den-einzelhandel-unterstuetzt/</link>
			<title>The importance of a digital business card: How Google supports retail</title>
			<description>Digitization has revolutionized the way businesses operate, and retail is no exception.</description>
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://smartstore.com/Bild: https://unsplash.com/de/fotos/qK8TuZ7T9N4" target="_blank"&gt;Image: https://unsplash.com/de/fotos/qK8TuZ7T9N4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Die Digitization has revolutionized the way businesses operate, and retail is no exception. But for small and medium-sized retailers in particular, the digital path is associated with many challenges. Google has launched a new initiative to address this very issue. Read &lt;a href="https://www.stores-shops.de/technology/e-commerce/google-wie-koennen-einzelhaendler-heute-im-omnichannel-ueberzeugen-und-inspirieren/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;how Google is helping retailers on their digital journey and how businesses can increase their visibility online.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In today's world, people are increasingly looking online for information about products and businesses. For this reason Google offers the &lt;a href="https://grow.google/intl/de/zukunfthandel/" target="_blank"&gt;Company Profile&lt;/a&gt; offers. This service represents, so to speak, the digital business card of a dealer on the Internet, which makes them visible in Google Search and on Google Maps. Here, information such as address, opening hours, contact details, pictures, current offers and even details on accessibility can be stored. It has been proven that businesses with a fully completed company profile receive nearly four times more website visits than those without a corresponding presence. They also receive five times more calls and four times more requests for directions to their stores. The company profile also offers the opportunity to advertise your own retail store without having to pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;A company's digital business card on Google is thus crucial to success in today's digital world. It increases visibility on the Internet and attracts potential customers. So if you don't have a Google business profile yet, now might be a good time to start. Your &lt;a href="https://mapsplatform.google.com/intl/de/solutions/retail/" target="_blank"&gt;digital business card&lt;/a&gt; could be the key to more online presence and ultimately more sales. Google provides you with the tools - use them!&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://smartstore.com/en/smartstore-represented-at-this-year-s-vendtra-trade-festival/</guid>
			<link>https://smartstore.com/en/smartstore-represented-at-this-year-s-vendtra-trade-festival/</link>
			<title>Smartstore represented at the Vendtra Trade Festival</title>
			<description>From 26. to 27. September, Munich's Olympic Park will once again be transformed into the heart of the vending and coffee machine industry. Smartstore will also be on site to present the implementation of the joint Smart Vending concept with Automatenland GmbH.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://smartstore.com/media/6370/content/news_vendtra_2023.png?size=680" type="image/png" length="67984" />
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;From &lt;strong&gt;26. to 27. September&lt;/strong&gt; Munich's Olympic Park will once again be transformed into the heart of the vending and
	coffee machine industry. The Vendtra trade fair, one of the most important events in Germany and Central Europe, offers professionals
	and companies an invaluable opportunity to exchange information about the latest trends and innovations. Smartstore will be presenting the joint &lt;a href="https://smartstore.com/de/smart-vending-die-revolution-des-einkaufens-am-automaten-2/"&gt;Smart Vending
		Concept &lt;/a&gt;with&lt;a href="https://smartstore.com/de/smartstore-und-die-automatenland-gmbh-beginnen-zusammenarbeit/"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Automatenland Ltd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fair focuses on various aspects of the industry, including table-top vending machines, coffee machines for the food service industry,
	Tower vending machines, payment and telemetry solutions, and special concepts for vending machine conversions and security locks. The entrance is
	free for all visitors after successful online registration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Grab &amp;amp; Go: Shopping made easy!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forward-looking concept of Smart Vending integrates state-of-the-art technologies such as. &lt;strong&gt;artificial intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; and
	&lt;strong&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/strong&gt; (IoT) and the &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft cloud-first approach&lt;/strong&gt;. Customers will enjoy a
	personalized and interactive shopping experience, while operators benefit from efficient management and monitoring of their vending machines
	benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By integrating artificial intelligence into smart vending, the machine can recognize customers' preferences and habits
	and offer tailored product suggestions and discount promotions. This not only increases customer satisfaction, but also leads to
	&lt;strong&gt;higher sales for the operators&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition, integrating vending machines into the cloud allows operators,
	Monitor the status of vending machines in real time, track inventory and identify maintenance needs in a timely manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Vending with smart self-service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vending and industrial machinery industry in Germany is booming, and Vendtra is playing a crucial role in promoting
	Innovation and the networking of companies in this sector. With more than 4 million vending machines and merchandise sales of
	11,8 billion euros, this industry in this country alone is &lt;strong&gt;an emerging market with great potential&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All industry professionals and companies who want to experience the future of the vending industry firsthand can join us at the
	booth A3 071-076 of the Automantenland GmbH come into conversation.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://smartstore.com/en/smartstore-nexoma-new-standards-for-innovative-e-commerce-solutions/</guid>
			<link>https://smartstore.com/en/smartstore-nexoma-new-standards-for-innovative-e-commerce-solutions/</link>
			<title>Smartstore &amp;amp; nexoma: New standards for innovative e-commerce solutions</title>
			<description>The remarkable partnership between SmartStore AG and nexoma GmbH will advance the digital transformation of companies.A powerful alliance between a robust e-commerce platform provider and a reliable IT company forms the foundation for business success.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://smartstore.com/media/6292/content/nexoma_4.png?size=680" type="image/png" length="35616" />
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today's business world requires effective presentation and marketing of products and services in the digital space. A powerful alliance between a robust e-commerce platform provider and a reliable IT company forms the foundation for business success. The remarkable partnership between SmartStore AG and nexoma GmbH will advance the digital transformation of companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The partnership between Smartstore and nexoma&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cooperation between SmartStore AG and nexoma is based on a strong technological collaboration. This enables companies to present their products optimally on different channels and offer an outstanding customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the core components of this partnership is the crossbase standard interface. This allows companies to pull data from various sources such as ERP systems and create catalogs. Connecting to marketplaces and importing XML files is also seamless with SmartStore's Catalog Express solution. Companies can manage their product data centrally and display and upload it via APIs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Product Management with PIM&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another outstanding feature of Smartstore is the seamless integration of a Product Information Management (PIM) system. nexoma's PIM Competence Center offers consulting and system integration for PIM projects. The PIM solution in Smartstore enables optimal organization and provision of product information for e-catalogs, print media, retailers or portals. Processes are optimized, workflows automated and resources freed up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;nexoma's data aggregators keep the wealth of plug-ins and product information in the stores up to date at all times. The experts at nexoma are pioneers in data communications and develop innovative solutions for the digital transformation. Through the partnership between SmartStore and nexoma, companies' product information always remains up to date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Flexibility for customized solutions&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smartstore offers a wealth of options for customization. Whether in local retail, online sales in the industrial landscape. Smartstore's customizability enables fast and straightforward implementations of individual solutions, without time-consuming and costly projects. This makes Smartstore the cost-efficient "made-to-measure" e-commerce platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Outlook for the future&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;"A store and marketplace solution based on open source sounds exciting. Both the technological orientation and especially the feature-rich scope of SmartStore convinced us. We would like to help shape the future with SmartStore AG and its customers and look forward to working together," says Fabian Fischer, responsible for sales, marketing and business development at nexoma.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The partnership between SmartStore and nexoma offers companies a unique opportunity to drive their digital transformation. SmartStore's powerful e-commerce software and nexoma's expertise in data communications and digital transformation enable companies to effectively showcase and market their products.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://smartstore.com/en/rueckerstattungsbetrug-auf-dem-vormarsch-was-onlinehaendler-wissen-sollten/</guid>
			<link>https://smartstore.com/en/rueckerstattungsbetrug-auf-dem-vormarsch-was-onlinehaendler-wissen-sollten/</link>
			<title>Refund fraud on the rise: What online retailers should know</title>
			<description>In so-called refund fraud, perpetrators order products on the Internet and later claim to the merchant that they never received the goods, thus obtaining a refund.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://smartstore.com/media/584/content/584.png?size=680" type="image/png" length="67714" />
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;So-called reimbursement fraud is becoming a bigger and bigger issue: in a recent online article &lt;a href="https://www.wiwo.de/unternehmen/handel/refund-masche-wenn-statt-des-iphones-nur-ein-haeufchen-sand-zurueckgeschickt-wird/29287488.html" target="_blank"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; Wirtschaftswoche" about the latest developments and tricks that online retailers should know about.&amp;nbsp;In refund fraud, perpetrators order products on the Internet and later claim never to have received them, thus obtaining a refund from the merchant.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assessments of the traders are different: While some are not noticing an increase in fraud, according to Wiwo, the Swiss/German tech retailer Galaxus reports an increase, especially since the start of the Corona pandemic. This is plausible, typically
	electronics assortments are highly susceptible to fraud. Used electronics provider Rebuy, for example, is also said to be strengthening its digital fraud defenses
	have. According to the Wiwo report, he sees a downward trend in fraud attempts, but notes that credit card fraud is
	continues to be a problem internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In spring 2021 the Federal Criminal Police Office conducted a raid on seven men suspected of being
		of belonging to the "German Refund Crew" and of having defrauded online retailers of hundreds of thousands of euros. In some cases, they send back cheaper or older items as returns and keep or sell
		the more expensive original merchandise. The "German Refund Crew" is said to be in more than. 600 of such cases and offered these
		Scam even offered in a Telegram group as a service.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar case was reported in Dortmund, Germany, where a lone perpetrator targeted online retailers in more than 1.600 cases for a total of 1,5 million
	Euro has defrauded. Another case involved a Spanish Amazon user who asked the company for 330.000 Euros by buying iPhones
	ordered, picked up the devices and filled the boxes with soil before sending them back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The German E-Commerce Association (BEVH) notes that in the year. 2022 increased chargebacks on credit card transactions,
	especially for amounts under  30  2022 and
	respectively. 50 Euro. The problem occurs mainly in transactions with buyers from third countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online merchants should be vigilant and use all possibilities of technical protection measures to prevent such fraud attempts from
	counteract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wiwo.de/unternehmen/handel/refund-masche-wenn-statt-des-iphones-nur-ein-haeufchen-sand-zurueckgeschickt-wird/29287488.html" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.wiwo.de/unternehmen/handel/refund-masche-wenn-statt-des-iphones-nur-ein-haeufchen-sand-zurueckgeschickt-wird/29287488.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>